Andrew (Drew) Anello

Brooklyn, NY 11211 | 646-334-8116 | drew.anello@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Throughout my time at General Assembly, I was the go-to student in my cohort to project lead and manage—delegating tasks, checking in on deadlines, and making sure the team worked together to complete a polished and pristine front end responsive product. This parallels my skills and experience managing a music lesson studio where I trained and scheduled new teachers, connected with parents, and updated the company's websites and deliverables.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL, Python

Libraries, and Frameworks: React.js, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap

Databases, and other: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API, Git, GitHub, Postman (testing), Google Analytics, AWS(Amazon Web Services), Cloud Computing, UX (user experience), UI (user interface), Cloud **Interpersonal skills:** Collaboration, Creative, Resourceful, Precise Execution, Leading With Curiosity, Research, Strong Verbal and Written Communication, Agile Methodology

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Wow Generator - GitHub | App -

Coding language used | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

A web app that calls an API to every "Wow!" Owen Wilson has said from 1996-2017. Users can search by the number of wow's in a movie and/or by the year.

- Created an app with a simple UI using CSS with flexbox layouts.
- Coordinated information through a third-party API in a seamless interface.
- Created a fully responsive design using CSS that readily adapts to all devices and screens.

NYC Pizza - GitHub | App -

Coding language used | Express.js, EJS, CSS

A full stack CRUD app that calls to MongoDB server where users can score, add, edit and delete pizza shops in NYC

- Created a full stack (front end and backend) application that allows users to add pizza shops, rate, review, and add the borough where the shop is located.
- Deployed application on Heroku so users can share with their friends.
- Created a fully responsive application that readily adapts to all devices and screens.

KonnectuZ - GitHub | App -

Coding language used | Express, React, Node.js, CSS

A social media full stack CRUD app that uses the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack where users can create an account and comment on other users' posts.

- Created an application that allows users to scroll through the user feed and see what users are posting i.e a picture or post.
- Users can sign into their existing account or create an account that has a username, password, and profile picture
- Created fully responsive design using CSS that readily adapts to all devices and screens.
- Deployed application using Netlify (client side) and Heroku (server side).

EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed, Freelance Front End Developer

New York, NY, 12/2021 - Present

- Oversaw all operations for my freelance web development company, including project management, customer support, design, and website deployment.
- Built and deployed websites using technologies such as CSS (CSS3), HTML(HTML5), JavaScript, WIX, WordPress, EJS, Express, Node.js, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass, and others.
- Used Search Engine Optimization (SEO) to have clients' websites rank higher in browsers to generate more website traffic.

Come Join the Band, Assistant Director

New York, NY, 12/2019 - 08/2022

- Oversaw all operations for a private music studio for students ages 3-adult, including sales, marketing, hiring, and scheduling"
- Updated and maintained the WordPress website which had an average of 10-12% growth in traffic every month.

• Conducted and scheduled daily guitar lessons and jam sessions for students.

Adorama, Audio and Computer Sales

New York, NY, 08/2018 - 12/2021

- Assisted clients with both audio and computer sales while consistently reaching monthly sales goal of \$120,000.
- Developed professional relationships with small to medium-sized businesses while managing a book of 150+ clients.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Remote, Certificate Expected: 10/2022

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Berklee College of Music

Remote: 09/2020-06/2022Completed

coursework in music production and computer science.